<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Databases on Alpha Coder</title>
    <link>https://alphacoder.xyz/tag/databases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Databases on Alpha Coder</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2020 to ∞. Try Catch Finally Solutions Ltd. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 13:46:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alphacoder.xyz/tag/databases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Database denormalization</title>
      <link>https://alphacoder.xyz/database-denormalization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 13:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alphacoder.xyz/database-denormalization/</guid>
      <description>Normalization is a vital part of database schema design. The goal is to structure a relational database so as to reduce redundancy and improve the integrity of data. Given this understanding, denormalization sounds rather counter-intuitive. Why would one want to make a database &amp;ldquo;less normalized&amp;rdquo;?
Well, it turns out that normalization comes at a performance cost for DB read operations. This is just fine for regular applications. However, read-heavy apps start to break at scale under this setup due to resource-intensive SQL queries involving joins, subqueries and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adminer — a simple GUI client for any DB</title>
      <link>https://alphacoder.xyz/adminer-a-simple-gui-client-for-any-db/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 06:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alphacoder.xyz/adminer-a-simple-gui-client-for-any-db/</guid>
      <description>In my search for a good database GUI client for PostgreSQL, I came across a light-weight and elegant GUI client called Adminer. Adminer is a is a full-featured database management tool built with PHP.
Before Adminer, I used pgAdmin III. I hoped it&amp;rsquo;d be similar to PHPMyAdmin but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t nearly as good in terms of the user interface and functionality. I found it difficult to navigate and had to write queries to perform even basic tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>