<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code Quality on Alpha Coder</title>
    <link>https://alphacoder.xyz/tag/code-quality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code Quality on Alpha Coder</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2017 to ∞. Nicholas Kajoh. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alphacoder.xyz/tag/code-quality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is readable code?</title>
      <link>https://alphacoder.xyz/what-is-readable-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alphacoder.xyz/what-is-readable-code/</guid>
      <description>Any code that I didn’t write or wrote more than 6 months ago is unreadable! — you, probably
Everyone writes readable code, and yet everyone complains about all the unreadable code they have to deal with on a daily. Of course, readability is subjective. But when developers say a certain piece of code is unreadable, they usually mean it requires high cognitive load to comprehend. So it makes sense that your code is usually readable to you regardless of how it looks because you wrote, and thus already understand it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with code debt</title>
      <link>https://alphacoder.xyz/dealing-with-code-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 19:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alphacoder.xyz/dealing-with-code-debt/</guid>
      <description>Code debt (or technical debt) is the amount of extra work that needs to be done due to choosing the easy way now instead of a better way that would take more time to complete. It&amp;rsquo;s human developer nature to always follow the path of least resistance e.g write spagetti code or fail to think things through before coding. As such dealing with code debt must be given priority by individuals and teams that want to build good software in a cost and time effective manner.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
