<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Startups on Alpha Coder</title>
    <link>http://alphacoder.xyz/tag/startups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Startups on Alpha Coder</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>© [ This Year ] Nicholas Kajoh</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 05:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://alphacoder.xyz/tag/startups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A tip for working on side projects</title>
      <link>http://alphacoder.xyz/side-project-tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 05:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alphacoder.xyz/side-project-tip/</guid>
      <description>Working on sides projects is a great way to build a portfolio for freelance or full-time job opportunities, crystallize your knowledge of programming languages/tools and development workflows and, if you play your cards right, earn some cool cash by commercializing your projects. But if you’ve worked on a side project before, you’re probably all too familiar with the trend that is brainstorming and coming up with great ideas, starting the project, stopping along the way, abandoning the project forever, and moving on to the next one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to land an internship at a great Nigerian startup</title>
      <link>http://alphacoder.xyz/land-an-internship-at-a-great-nigerian-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 07:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alphacoder.xyz/land-an-internship-at-a-great-nigerian-startup/</guid>
      <description>Getting an internship at a great company is one of the best ways to kick-start your career in tech. You’ll get to learn from top-notch developers/designers and work on ambitious and exciting projects/products. Plus if you do well, you’ll likely be given a full-time offer which is pretty neat.
Here are some tips on how to land an internship at a great Nigerian startup…
Do your homework I remember being caught off guard when asked about the company I was applying to by my interviewer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>